<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>



<!-- Remember, that top line is not really a tag. 
    It is a processing instruction that tells the computer that this is an XML file 
    and that it should be validated against a schema online at the TEI web site.-->

<TEI xml:id="Howells_Intro.xml" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <!-- In the above line, change the xml:id to the id of your file: stnic.YYYYMM.001 
        (the 001 can be changed to 002, etc if we are encoding more than one piece from a particular month) -->

    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="a" type="main">Noble Deeds of Woman.</title>
                
            </titleStmt>


            <!-- The following section records information about who is publishing this file. -->
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2019</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</publisher>
                
                <date>2019</date>
                <availability>
                    <p>This file is freely distributed and
                        licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0
                        Unported License</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>

            <!-- A place to record additional info about the material -->
            <notesStmt>
                <note type="project">This file was produced for English 478/878: Digital Archives and Editions, Department of English, University of Nebraska-Lincoln, Spring 2019.</note>
            </notesStmt>


            <!-- This section describes the source, i.e., the document(s) you are encoding. -->

            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <!-- Insert title and date again here -->
                    <title level="a">Noble Deeds of Woman</title>
                    
                    <!-- Make an author or illustrator line for each one mentioned in the piece. -->
                    <author>Elizabeth Starling</author>
                    <publisher>Cary, Lea, And Blanchard.</publisher>
                    <date when="1836">1836</date>
                    <!-- Note that @when allows a regularized form of the date -->
                  
                    <pubPlace>Philadelphia</pubPlace>
                    <orgName>Carey, Lea, and Blanchard.</orgName>
                    <note>transcribed from Noble Deeds of Woman first ed., Special Collections, University Libraries, University of Nebraska-Lincoln. </note>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <editorialDecl>
                <p/>
            </editorialDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <particDesc>
                <listPerson type="referenced">
                    <person xml:id="starling">
                        <persName>Elizabeth Starling</persName>
                        <note>Author of text</note>
                    </person>
                    <person xml:id="oldcarey">
                        <persName>Matthew Carey</persName>
                        <note>Founder of publishing company. Began publishin in 1785 at Pennsylvania Evening Herald. Established Matthew Carey &amp; Sons in 1817. Retired in 1824</note>
                    </person>
                    <person xml:id="carey">
                        <persName>Henry Charles Carey</persName>
                        <note>Son of Matthew Carey. Established Carey, Lea, and Blanchard in 1833</note>
                    </person>
                    <person xml:id="blanchard">
                        <persName>William Blanchard</persName>
                        <note>Helped establish Carey, Lea, and Blanchard in 1833</note>
                    </person>
                    <person xml:id="lea">
                        <persName>Isaac Lea</persName>
                        <note>Step son of Matthew Carey. Helped establish Carey, Lea, and Blanchard in 1833</note>
                    </person>
                    
                </listPerson>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>


        <!-- This section records whose hands have been in the file. -->

        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="20190214">
                <name>Phillip Howells</name>
                Encoded.</change>
        </revisionDesc>
        
    </teiHeader>

 
    <text>
        <body><p></p></body>
   <!--Haven't done any of this yet....
        <front>
            <pb facs="01.jpg"/>
            <head>CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHTS IN WAR-TIME</head>

            <epigraph>
                <quote><title>First Amendment to the Constitution </title> Congress shall make no
                    law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise
                    thereof; or abridging the freedom of speech, or of the press; or the right of
                    the people peaceably to assemble, and to petition the Government for a redress
                    of grievances. </quote>
            </epigraph>

            <docImprint>PUBLISHED BY <orgName>AMERICAN UNION AGAINST MILITARISM</orgName>
                <address><addrLine>Munsey Building, Washington, D. C. </addrLine>
            <addrLine>New York Office 
            70 Fifth Avenue</addrLine></address>
                <docDate>May, 1917 </docDate>
                <figure>
                    <figDesc>Union bug, Allied Printing Trades Council Washington</figDesc>
                </figure></docImprint>
            <pb facs="02.jpg"/>

            <docImprint><orgName>AMERICAN UNION AGAINST MILITARISM</orgName>
                <roleName>OFFICERS <name><persName>LILLIAN D. WALD</persName></name>,
                        <roleName>Chairman</roleName>
                    <name><persName>AMOS PINCHOT</persName></name>,
                        <roleName>Vice-Chairman</roleName>
                    <name><persName>L. HOLLINGSWORTH WOOD</persName></name>,
                        <roleName>Treasurer</roleName>
                    <name><persName>CRYSTAL EASTMAN</persName></name>,
                        <roleName>Secretary</roleName>
                    <name><persName>CHARLES T. HALLINAN</persName></name>, <roleName>Editorial
                        Director.</roleName>
                    <name><persName>ROGER N. BALDWIN</persName></name>, <roleName>Field
                        Secretary</roleName>
                </roleName>
                <roleName>EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE</roleName>
                <name><persName>JANE ADDAMS</persName>, <placeName>Illinois</placeName>
                </name>
                <name><persName>EMILY G. BALCH</persName>,
                    <placeName>Massachusetts</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>A. A. BERLE</persName>, <placeName>Massachusetts</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>HERBERT S. BIGELOW</persName>, <placeName>Ohio</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>SOPHONISBA P. BRECKINRIDGE</persName>,
                        <placeName>Illinois</placeName>.</name>
                <name><persName>WILLIAM F. COCHRAN</persName>,
                    <placeName>Maryland</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>MAX EASTMAN</persName>, <placeName>New York</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>JOHN LOVEJOY ELLIOTT</persName>, <placeName>New
                    York</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>MRS. GLENDOWER EVANS</persName>,
                        <placeName>Massachusetts</placeName>
                </name>
                <name><persName>ZONA GALE</persName>, <placeName>Wisconsin</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>JOHN HAYNES HOLMES</persName>, <placeName>New
                    York</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>DAVID STARR JORDAN</persName>,
                    <placeName>California</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>PAUL U. KELLOGG</persName>, <placeName>New York</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>AGNES B. LEACH</persName>, <placeName>New York</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>ALICE LEWISOHN</persName>, <placeName>New York</placeName></name>
                <name>OWEN R. LOVEJOY, New York </name>
                <name><persName>FREDERICK LYNCH</persName>, <placeName>New York</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>JOHN. A. McSPARRAN</persName>,
                    <placeName>Pennsylvania</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>JAMES H. MAURER</persName>,
                    <placeName>Pennsylvania</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>HENRY R. MUSSEY</persName>, <placeName>New York</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>SCOTT NEARING</persName>, <placeName>Ohio</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>NORMAN THOMAS</persName>, <placeName>New York</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>OSWALD GARRISON VILLARD</persName>, <placeName>New
                    York</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>JAMES P. WARBASSE</persName>, <placeName>New York</placeName></name>
                <name><persName>STEPHEN S. WISE</persName>, <placeName>New York</placeName></name>
                <roleName>Committee on Constitutional Rights </roleName>
                <name><persName>AMOS PINCHOT</persName>, <roleName>Chairman</roleName></name>
                <name><persName>MAX EASTMAN</persName></name>
                <name><persName>AGNES B. LEACH</persName></name>
                <name><persName>STEPHEN S. WISE </persName></name>
                <name><persName>HERBERT S. BIGELOW </persName></name>
                <name><persName>SCOTT NEARING </persName></name>
                <name><persName>WM. F. COCHRAN A</persName></name>
                <milestone unit="shortLine"/>
                <orgName>AMERICAN LEGAL DEFENSE LEAGUE</orgName>
                <address><addrLine>261 Broadway, New York</addrLine></address>
                <name><persName>HARRY WEINBERGER</persName>,
                <roleName>Counsel</roleName></name></docImprint>
        </front>
        <body>
            <pb facs="03.jppg"/>

            <div type="section">
                <head>CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHTS IN WAR-TIME </head>

                <p>Constitutional rights are being seriously invaded throughout the United States
                    under pressure of war. Men are arrested and fined for criticising the Government
                    or the President. Halls are refused for meetings; meetings are broken up;
                    pamphlets and literature opposing war are confiscated and the authors haled into
                    court.</p>

                <p>In short, the guarantees of the Federal Constitution have been suspended at the
                    dictate of petty officials who would compel conformity on the part of all
                    citizens to their conception of war policies. </p>

                <p>Such a time is a challenge to all patriots to maintain the liberties guaranteed
                    by the Constitution.</p>

                <p>In order that full information may be readily accessible to every interested
                    citizen, the <emph rend="bold">American Union Against Militarism</emph>
                    publishes these facts. Further information about specific issues can be obtained
                    by addressing an organization recently formed to protect these rights in
                    wartime&#8212;the <emph rend="bold">American Legal Defense League,</emph> 261
                    Broadway, New York City. This League is utilizing committees and organizations
                    in cities and towns throughout the country to assist it, and is securing the
                    services of lawyers to handle cases throughout the United States.</p>
            </div>

            <div type="section">
                <head>THE ISSUES </head>
                <p>The practical questions affecting free speech, free press and assembly which
                    chiefly come up during War-time are these:</p>
                <list>
                    <item>1. How far can citizens criticize the conduct of the war, war legislation
                        and public officials without going beyond their constitutional
                        rights?</item>
                    <item>2. How far can they express opposition to war in general, or this war in
                        particular, and how far can they advocate peace?</item>
                    <item>3. How far can they express sympathy with the enemy without going beyond
                        their constitutional rights? </item>
                    <item>4. Have the police the right to enter private meetings held on private
                        property? </item>
                    <item>5. Have they the right to break up orderly public meetings on private
                        property? </item>
                    <item>6. Have the police the right to break up meetings held on the streets, or
                        stop the distribution of literature in public places?</item>
                    <item>7. Have the police the right to prevent a man from speaking on the ground
                        that what he proposes to say, judging from announcements in advance, is
                        treasonable or likely to incite to riot? </item>
                    <item>8. What authority have prosecuting officials to interfere with meetings,
                        distribution of literature or public utterances? </item>
                </list>
                <p>Harry Weinberger, counsel of the American Legal Defense League, has submitted to
                    the American Union these answers to the above questions:</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>(1) FREE SPEECH AND FREE PRESS </head>
                <head type="sub"><emph rend="bold">The Constitution permits citizens to criticize officials, and
                        war legislation, to oppose war the conduct of the war <fw place="bottom"
                            type="number">3</fw>
                        <pb facs="04.jpg"/> and even to express sympathy with the enemy. The
                        Constitution is not suspended by a declaration of war. </emph></head>
                <p>The theory of the first amendment of the Constitution is that a citizen may say
                    anything he pleases, but that he is liable for any injury which his utterances
                    may cause and may be proceeded against for such injury. Congress may by statute
                    attempt to define in war-time what are seditious or treasonable utterances, but
                    the validity of such legislation is extremely doubtful. There are a few legal
                    points in this connection which need to be made clear. </p>

                <div>
                    <div>
                        <head rend="bold">(1) No man can be tried for treason for anything that he
                            may say or write.</head>
                        <p>"Treason" is defined in the United States Constitution as consisting only
                            in (a) "levying war against the United States, or (b) adhering to their
                            enemies, giving them aid and comfort." <emph rend="bold">No other act
                                can be declared to constitute the offense. Congress can neither
                                extend nor restrict nor define the crime.</emph> [ U. S. v.
                            Greathouse, 26 Fed. Case 18; 26 Fed. Case, 15,254.] </p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head rend="bold">Levying War</head>
                        <p>(a) Chief Justice Marshall, in defining "treason " in the trial of Aaron
                            Burr said:</p>
                        <p><quote>"It is not enough to be leagued in the conspiracy and that war be
                                levied, but it is also necessary to perform a part. That part is the
                                act of levying war." </quote></p>
                        <p><quote>"A levying of war (or treason) without having recourse to rules of
                                construction or artificial reasoning, would seem to be nothing short
                                of the employment, or at least of the embodying of a military force
                                armed and arrayed in a warlike manner for the purpose of forcibly
                                subverting the government, dismembering the union, or destroying the
                                legislative function of Congress. These troops should be so armed
                                and so directed as to leave no doubt that the United States or their
                                government were the immediate object of the attack."</quote> [U. S.
                            v. Hoxie, 26 Fed. Case, 397.]</p>
                    </div>

                    <div>
                        <head rend="bold">Aid and Comfort to the Enemy</head>

                        <p>(b) Mere expression of opinion indicative of sympathy with the public
                            enemy although sufficient to justify a strong feeling of indignation
                            against the individual and the suspicion that he is at heart a traitor,
                            are not sufficient under the Constitution and laws of the United States
                            to warrant a conviction of treason. [In re Charge to Grand Jury, 30 Fed.
                            Case, No. 18,272.] </p>
                        <p>The crime of treason is not completed until there is an overt act, it
                            being not sufficient that there exists a mere conspiracy to over-throw
                            the government or an intention to commit treason, or treasonable words,
                            whether oral, written or printed. [U. S. v. Burr, 25 Fed. Case No. 14,
                            692A. U. S. v. Pryor, 27 Fed. Case, No. 16,096.] </p>
                    
                </div>

                <div>
                    <head type="sub"><emph rend="bold">(2) No utterances can be proceeded against as seditious.
                        Congress at one time passed what are known as the Alien and Sedition Acts,
                        which were condemned by public sentiment and repealed.</emph> </head>

                    <p>Story on the Constitution says of the Sedition Law:</p>

                    <p><quote> The Sedition Law declared it a public crime punishable with fine and
                            imprisonment for any persons unlawfully to combine and <pb facs="05.jpg"
                            />conspire together with intent to oppose any measure or measures of the
                            United States, etc. ; or with such intent to counsel, advise or attempt
                            to procure any insurrection, unlawful assembly or combination; or to
                            write, print, utter or publish or cause or procure to be written, etc.,
                            or willingly to assist in writing, etc., any false, scandalous or
                            malicious writing or writings against the Government of the United
                            States or either House of Congress or the President with intent to
                            defame them or to bring them into contempt or disrepute or to excite
                            against them the hatred of the people or to stir up sedition; or to
                            excite any unlawful combination for opposing or resisting any law or any
                            lawful act of the President; or to resist, oppose or defeat any such law
                            or act; or to aid, encourage or abet any hostile designs of any foreign
                            nations against the United States. </quote></p>

                    <p><quote>"It provided, however, that the truth of the writing or libel might be
                            given in evidence; and that the jury who tried the case should have the
                            right to determine the law and the fact under the direction of the court
                            as in other cases. </quote></p>

                    <p><quote>"The constitutionality of the Alien and Sedition Acts was assailed
                            with great earnestness and ability at the time and was defended with
                            equal masculine vigor. . . . They were impugned as not conformable to
                            the letter or spirit of the Constitution; and as unconstitutional in
                            their principles with the rights of citizens and the liberty of the
                            press. . . . </quote></p>

                    <p><quote>"It was added that the Sedition Act was open to the same objection and
                            was expressly forbidden by one of the amendments of the Constitution. .
                            . . </quote></p>

                    <p><quote>"At present it does not seem necessary to present more than this
                            general outline as the measures are not likely to be renewed and as the
                            doctrines on which they are maintained and denounced are not materially
                            different from those which have been already considered. </quote></p>

                    <p><quote>"The Alien and Sedition Acts were beyond all question condemned by
                            public sentiment. . . The Sedition Act was clearly in the highest degree
                            impolitic, and as the prosecution showed was susceptible of being used
                            for the purpose of oppression and terrorism, and these facts afford
                            reason abundant for its condemnation." </quote></p>

                </div>
                <div>
                    <p><emph rend="bold">(3) As a practical matter in war-time the authorities,
                            federal or local, will be inclined to proceed against men who criticize
                            the government, who oppose war or express sympathy with the enemy. They
                            will be sure to find some ground upon which to proceed, even though it
                            may be under an ordinance governing "disorderly conduct."</emph> All
                        persons who are opposing, by speech or in print, any act of the government,
                        or laws which they regard as unjust, should do so by <emph rend="bold"
                            >advocating legal means of opposition.</emph> To advocate <emph
                            rend="bold">resistance</emph> to the conscription law would result in
                        the prosecution of the person who counseled it. But to advocate the repeal
                        of the conscription law, and to say anything one chooses in advocacy of that
                        repeal, could not be held illegal. <emph rend="bold">All meetings devoted to
                            opposition to laws, and all literature issued for that purpose, should
                            clearly state that they are for the purpose of petitioning the
                            government to repeal the laws.</emph></p>
                </div>
            </div>
            </div>

<div>
    <head rend="bold">(2) RIGHT OF ASSEMBLY IN PRIVATE PLACES </head>
    <head type="sub"><emph rend="bold">The police have no legal right to enter private meetings held on private property, nor to break up orderly public meetings held on private property, nor to confiscate literature or papers without a warrant. </emph></head>
    
    <p>The fourth amendment to the Constitution reads: </p>
    
    <quote><p>"The right of the people to be secure in their persons, houses, papers, and effects, against unreasonable searches and seizures, shall not be violated, and no warrants shall issue but upon probable cause, supported by oath or affirmation, and particularly describing the place to be searched and the persons or things to be seized." </p></quote>
    
    <p>Judge William J. Gaynor of the New York Supreme Court, said [Murphy v. Snitzpan, 15 Misc. (N. V.) 500]: </p>
    
   <p><quote>"The police have no right to forcibly interfere with citizens except to arrest them for crime. The contrary has become all too common. The like is not permitted in any free government in the world, except in some of the large cities of this country, and it will not be tolerated there much longer. A citizen has as much right to arrest even a policeman committing a criminal offense as a policeman has to arrest a citizen. To be plain about it, as the citizens do not want to be doing police duty, they hire policemen for that purpose, but do not thereby make them masters nor give them any more right to interfere with individuals than they have themselves."</quote></p>
    
    <p>Judge Samuel Seabury, Judge of the Court of Appeals of New York, said [Fairmont Athletic Club v. Bingham, 61 Misc. (N. V.) 419]: </p>
    
    <p><quote>"The duty of police officers, like all other public servants, is fixed and defined by law, and when they act contrary to this duty they become wrongdoers and violators of law. It is an essential characteristic of free government that every official is himself subject to the law and that none is above it. . . . </quote></p>
    
    <p><quote>"Police officers have no right to enter without a warrant upon private property such as dwellings or club houses because they suspect that misdemeanors are or may be committed therein. . . . It would be difficult to imagine a more odious form of oppression than this so-called right to search private premises to ascertain whether crimes are being committed. Lord Camden declared1 that 'to invade a man's house by virtue of a nameless warrant in order to procure evidence is worse than the Spanish inquisition; a law under which no Englishman would wish to live an hour; it was a most daring public attack made upon the liberty of the subject.' If there is no such law (allowing officers to enter private places) and none has been or can be cited, then, as Lord Camden said, 'the silence of the books is an authority against the defendant.' </quote></p>
    
    <p><quote>"At common law the king had no right to enter without warrant the house of his humblest subject on the mere suspicion that the subject had committed or was about to commit a crime.  The 
    
    <note type="authorial">1 In Huckle v. Money, 2 Wilson, 205, 207. </note>
    
    
    <fw place="bottom" type="number"> </fw>
    
    <pb facs="06.jpg"/>
    
    Governor of this State in whom the chief executive power of the people is vested by the Constitution has no such right.</quote></p> 
    
    <p><quote>"It seems, however, that in the opinion of these defendants (police officers) the limitations which restrain the actions of kings and governors are but ropes of sand to a New York policeman. They seem to imagine that because they are police officials they are free from all constitutional restraints and have a commission which entitles them to rove at will into the private houses, clubs or places of business of citizens. <emph rend="bold">It cannot be too often reiterated that they have no such right."</emph></quote></p>
</div>
            <div>
                <head rend="bold">(3) RIGHT OF ASSEMBLY IN PUBLIC PLACES </head>
                <head type="sub"><emph rend="bold">The police have no right to break up meetings held on the street or other public places, or to prevent a man from speaking before he says anything on which to make a charge. The police have not the right to stop the distribution of literature either on the streets or in meetings.</emph> <hi rend="italics">[People v. Samuel W . Simpson, Court of General Sessions, N. Y., Judge Joseph F. Mulqueen, Jan. 5th, 1915; City of Philadelphia v. Brabender, 51 Atl. 374; People v. Armstrong, 73 Mich. 288.]</hi> </head>
                
                <div><p>(1) Despite the opinions of the courts and the provisions of the Constitution, the police in many cities do break up public meetings and arrest speakers if they say things the police do not like, or if they are announced to talk on subjects the police and officials regard as "dangerous." </p>
                
                    <list><item>1st. Be sure the advertising for the meetings does not contain advocacy of illegal purposes. See that advertising reads for the repeal or enactment of laws; for discussion; or for petitioning the government. </item>
                
                <item>2nd. If you wish to be almost certain to avoid police interference, have admission to your meeting, if held on private property, by ticket only, either paid or complimentary. Advertise it as being open to members of the organization "and their friends." The police in most cities will not interfere with meetings of this character. </item>
                
                <item>3rd. It is also possible, if the police threaten to stop any meeting, to go into court and obtain an injunction prohibiting them from interfering. In case the police attempt to stop a meeting in advance by notifying the proprietor of the meeting-place not to allow the meeting to be held, or by notifying the speakers they will be arrested if they attempt to speak, a good lawyer should be consulted at once and legal steps taken to prevent police interference.</item> </list></div>
                
                <div><p>(2) The right to hold meetings in public places is modified in many cities by ordinances requiring permits to be obtained. Such ordinances are doubtless unconstitutional, but they are, nevertheless, enforced by the police. In many cities meetings are broken up on the ground that they interfere with street traffic. It has been held by many courts that such meetings cannot be interfered with unless they are actually blocking the traffic, and that if a lane is left open for vehicles and pedestrians to pass, the meeting may continue. Local police regulations must determine how and where street meetings can be held. </p></div>
                <fw place="bottom" type="number">7</fw>
                
                <pb facs="07.jpg"/>
                
                <div><p>(3) The police have no more legal right to stop the distribution of literature on the street than they have to stop the distribution of newspapers on the street. Some cities have ordinances which forbid the distribution of literature on the streets for the purpose of preventing the streets from being littered. But it has been held by a number of courts that only the person who throws the literature on the street, not the person who hands it to him, can be found guilty under such an ordinance.</p></div>
                
                
            </div>
            <div>
                <head rend="bold">(4) INVASIVE ACTS BY PROSECUTING OFFICIALS </head>
                
               <p> <emph rend="bold">In addition to interference by the police, the rights of free speech and free press may he invaded by prosecuting officials and district attorneys who in some cases summon persons to appear before them and to produce their records, literature, names of members of an organization, and the like.</emph> In some cases offices are raided and literature and papers taken in charge by federal or local officials. No prosecuting official or district attorney has the right to summon citizens to answer inquiries, or to enter a private office to take papers without warrant. They have no right to question citizens about their activities or utterances until a formal charge has been made in court.</p>
                   <p>The only way to meet such interference by prosecuting officials is to assert constitutional rights, to decline to give information or give up papers without a warrant, and to consult an attorney at once. </p>
            </div>
            
            <div>
                <head rend="bold">(5) THE "SPY BILL"</head> 
                
                <p>The effect on constitutional rights of the so-called "Spy" or Espionage bill, pending in Congress at the time this pamphlet is being printed, will be considerable. A special statement will be issued later dealing with the provisions of that bill in relation to the statements made in this pamphlet. It seems likely, however, that no provision of the bill will abridge these rights definitely, and that if any provision does, it will be taken at once into the courts. </p>
                
               <p> Much will depend on how such war-time legislation is administered. The administration at Washington professes a desire to be liberal, and it is to be hoped that the federal authorities who will enforce the provisions of this act, will not undertake seriously to interfere with established rights. </p>
            </div>
            <milestone unit="shortLine"/>
            <div>
                <p>Further information on specific issues can be secured by ad-dressing the American Legal Defense League, 261 Broadway, New York City. </p>
                
                <p>The organization of the work outside of New York City has been undertaken by the American Union Against Militarism and its local branches and committees. The names of attorneys in other cities than New York will be furnished on application. </p>
                
                <p>The American Union will be glad to have the names of responsible lawyers in any city who will volunteer their services in such cases.</p> 
                <closer>Address<address> 
                <orgName>AMERICAN UNION AGAINST MILITARISM,</orgName> 
                <addrLine>New York Office, 70 Fifth Avenue.</addrLine></address></closer>
            </div>
            
        </body>
    -->
    </text>

</TEI>
